Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Soporte Admin Mira en kissasia.cam o kisskh.org
Siming.
Simulación.
Our servant said it was chaos out there.
Nuestro sirviente dijo que afuera había caos.
Come practice with me.
Ven a practicar conmigo.
Brother.
Hermano.
Brother, stop. It's too hot.
Hermano, para. Hace demasiado calor.
What's wrong with you?
¿Qué sucede contigo?
Mom asked me to protect you.
Mamá me pidió que te protegiera.
I can't protect you if I don't practice.
No puedo protegerte si no practico.
Have at you.
Tenlo a mano.
I...
I...
All right.
Está bien.
Brother.
Hermano.
If someone
Si alguien
wants us
nos quiere
to live a poor life again,
vivir una vida pobre de nuevo,
will you allow it?
¿Lo permitirás?
Is he powerful?
¿Es él poderoso?
Is he more powerful than you?
¿Es él más poderoso que tú?
He's more powerful than me now.
Él es más poderoso que yo ahora.
I'm not afraid of him.
No le tengo miedo.
You'll be more powerful than him soon.
Serás más poderoso que él pronto.
Mom said,
Mamá dijo:
"Dogs eat shit wherever they go."
"Los perros comen mierda donde quiera que van".
"Wolves eat meat wherever they go."
"Los lobos comen carne dondequiera que van."
Who are you referring to?
¿A quién te refieres?
You're a wolf.
Eres un lobo.
I'm a wolf dog.
Soy un perro lobo.
Don't worry, brother.
No te preocupes, hermano.
If someone wants us to go back to the old days,
Si alguien quiere que volvamos a los viejos tiempos,
either I kill him, or he kills me.
O lo mato yo, o él me mata.
You might as well kill him.
También podrías matarlo.
We're going to have a good life.
Vamos a tener una buena vida.
[Treasure at Dawn] ♪Reach the highest level♪
[Tesoro al amanecer] ♪Alcanza el nivel más alto♪
♪Reach the state of no desire, illuminate the virtuous light♪
♪Alcanza el estado de no deseo, ilumina la luz virtuosa♪
♪Man is upright because he is moral, and he is strong because he is upright♪
♪El hombre es recto porque es moral, y es fuerte porque es recto♪
♪Upright, strong, and fair♪
♪Recto, fuerte y justo♪
♪I am the fire♪
♪Yo soy el fuego♪
♪Burning out all desires♪
♪Quemando todos los deseos♪
♪River can't put me out♪
♪El río no puede apagarme♪
♪Yang's beginning leads to development. Wu Chi creates Tai Chi♪
♪El comienzo de Yang conduce al desarrollo. Wu Chi crea el Tai Chi♪
♪People mistake their bodily form, forgetting the true mind within♪
♪La gente confunde su forma corporal, olvidando la verdadera mente que hay en su interior♪
♪People make their own enemies♪
♪La gente crea sus propios enemigos♪
♪Books are all about reason. People are full of purpose♪
♪Los libros son pura razón. La gente tiene un propósito.♪
♪People are overrun by illusions♪
♪La gente está invadida por ilusiones♪
♪They are fascinated by illusions♪
♪Están fascinados por las ilusiones♪
♪With a pure mind, sitting in the clouds♪
♪Con una mente pura, sentado en las nubes♪
♪Watching people creating dreams♪
♪Observando a la gente crear sueños♪
♪Is it painful to live in the world?♪
♪¿Es doloroso vivir en el mundo?♪
♪Learn from nature. Forget all your desires♪
Aprende de la naturaleza. Olvida todos tus deseos.
♪How about clearing all my thoughts?♪
♪¿Qué tal si aclaras todos mis pensamientos?♪
♪Moths fly into the fire♪
♪Las polillas vuelan hacia el fuego♪
♪The fire melts old shackles♪
♪El fuego derrite viejos grilletes♪
♪Today, I know it's me♪
♪Hoy sé que soy yo♪
[Treasure at Dawn]
[Tesoro al amanecer]
[Episode 16] [Storyteller Cleared, Another Death at Lei's]
[Episodio 16] [Narrador exonerado, otra muerte en casa de Lei]
Is it comfortable?
¿Es cómodo?
What
Qué
brings you here?
¿Qué te trae por aquí?
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
I didn't wash the horse you told me.
No lavé el caballo que me dijiste.
Is this Hua Lei's horse?
¿Es este el caballo de Hua Lei?
I've checked it.
Lo he comprobado.
It's not hurt or sick.
No está herido ni enfermo.
It's all right.
Está todo bien.
It looks upset.
Parece molesto.
Since Hua Lei died,
Desde que murió Hua Lei,
it hadn't eaten for two days.
No había comido durante dos días.
I'll give you some herbs.
Te daré algunas hierbas.
Mix it in the hay.
Mézclalo con el heno.
Maybe it will eat it.
Quizás se lo coma.
Everyone has their own destiny, and so do horses.
Cada uno tiene su propio destino y los caballos también.
Don't meddle in things.
No te metas en las cosas.
Otherwise, you will get in trouble.
De lo contrario, te meterás en problemas.
What do you mean?
¿Qué quieres decir?
That's a piece of advice.
Esto es un consejo.
Don't look
No mires
into Xubu Huai and Hua Lei's deaths.
sobre las muertes de Xubu Huai y Hua Lei.
War
Guerra
is inevitable.
Es inevitable.
Only by finding out the truth
Sólo descubriendo la verdad
will no more people die.
¿No morirá más gente?
You're a good person.
Eres una buena persona.
But you're silly.
Pero eres tonto.
He's not smarter
Él no es más inteligente
than you.
que tú.
I'm not
No lo soy
as smart as you.
Tan inteligente como tú.
I still didn't get what I wanted.
Todavía no conseguí lo que quería.
The city is in a panic.
La ciudad está en pánico.
Ma Gang is keeping an eye on me.
Ma Gang me está vigilando.
I can't do it.
No puedo hacerlo
But I've been trying to find it.
Pero he estado tratando de encontrarlo.
I'll make sure
Me aseguraré de que
you get it.
Lo entiendes.
You tried hard to climb up.
Te esforzaste mucho para subir.
Do you think it's not that good?
¿Crees que no es tan bueno?
It's better
Es mejor
than being trampled.
que ser pisoteado.
Before you can trample on me,
Antes de que puedas pisotearme,
you'd better
Será mejor que lo hagas
keep your thoughts to yourself.
Guarda tus pensamientos para ti mismo.
No more excuses.
No más excusas.
All I want is the jade plate.
Todo lo que quiero es la placa de jade.
I know.
Lo sé.
You're a lunatic.
Eres un lunático.
You're not afraid of death.
No tienes miedo a la muerte.
I don't know if your brother is afraid of death.
No sé si tu hermano tiene miedo a la muerte.
The people of Ma Gang are going to make some moves.
La gente de Ma Gang va a hacer algunos movimientos.
I'll send people to deal with them.
Enviaré gente para ocuparse de ellos.
Do your job.
Haz tu trabajo.
Sir.
Señor.
A bowl of meat soup.
Un tazón de sopa de carne.
Okay.
Bueno.
This seat is taken.
Este asiento está ocupado.
I'll leave if he comes.
Me iré si él viene.
Mr. Feng, don't worry.
Señor Feng, no se preocupe.
Here. Enjoy.
Aquí. Disfruta.
Are you here to see me?
¿Estas aquí para verme?
I want you to find something.
Quiero que encuentres algo.
The Hearsay-capturing Pavilion
El pabellón que captura rumores
can't find it.
No lo puedo encontrar.
Name your price.
Di tu precio
It's not about the money.
No se trata de dinero.
Sir.
Señor.
I'll pay his bill.
Yo pagaré su cuenta.
Okay.
Bueno.
Steward Sun, enjoy your food.
Mayordomo Sun, disfrute su comida.
See you later.
Hasta luego.
Hearsay-capturing Pavilion.
Pabellón que captura rumores.
Good.
Bien.
Xichuan is big.
Xichuan es grande.
I don't believe the Hearsay-capturing Pavilion
No creo en el Pabellón que captura rumores
is the only one who can find it.
Es el único que puede encontrarlo.
Authentic calligraphy works and paintings.
Obras de caligrafía y pinturas auténticas.
Have a look.
Echa un vistazo.
Calligraphy works and paintings.
Obras de caligrafía y pinturas.
Bamboo baskets.
Cestas de bambú.
It's weird.
Es raro.
I have a strange feeling.
Tengo una sensación extraña.
Am I sick?
¿Estoy enfermo?
Bamboo baskets. Have a look.
Cestas de bambú. Echa un vistazo.
Fang Zhiyuan talks about heroes.
Fang Zhiyuan habla de héroes.
He doesn't talk about the past, only the present.
No habla del pasado, sólo del presente.
Ladies and gentlemen, come early.
Damas y caballeros, vengan temprano.
- Do you want to hear it? - Yes.
-¿Quieres oírlo?-Sí.
Come on.
Vamos.
Get a cushion.
Consigue un cojín.
Okay.
Bueno.
[Inviting Moon House] Anyone else?
[Invitando a Moon House] ¿Alguien más?
Me.
A mí.
Okay.
Bueno.
Why are there so many people?
¿Por qué hay tanta gente?
Sir, you must be new here.
Señor, usted debe ser nuevo aquí.
Something big
Algo grande
happened in Xichuan.
Ocurrió en Xichuan.
Xubu Huai, Hua Lei.
Xubu Huai, Hua Lei.
You're right.
Tienes razón.
The night
La noche
after Mr. Fang told their stories,
Después de que el Sr. Fang contara sus historias,
they died.
ellos murieron
Rumor has it
Los rumores dicen que
that the little ghost Mr. Fang raised
que el pequeño fantasma que crió el señor Fang
killed them at night on orders.
Los mataron por la noche siguiendo órdenes.
Don't you want to know
¿No quieres saberlo?
who's next?
¿Quién es el siguiente?
You're right.
Tienes razón.
Give a ticket.
Dar un boleto.
Sir.
Señor.
We're selling extra seats.
Estamos vendiendo asientos adicionales.
You will get a cushion and sit outside the building.
Recibirás un cojín y te sentarás fuera del edificio.
The price is the same as the first-class seat.
El precio es el mismo que el del asiento de primera clase.
Don't be angry.
No te enojes
We don't bargain.
No negociamos.
Do you want to buy a ticket?
¿Quieres comprar un billete?
Screw you.
Púdrete.
Get out of here, you pauper.
¡Sal de aquí, pobrecito!
Come on.
Vamos.
Anyone else who wants to hear it?
¿Alguien más quiere escucharlo?
Are you being bullied?
¿Estás sufriendo acoso?
- Outside seats were also sold out. - I can't get in.
- Los asientos de afuera también estaban agotados. - No puedo entrar.
- Anyone else? - Let's go. I'll handle it.
- ¿Alguien más? - Vamos. Yo me encargo.
Come on.
Vamos.
Young Mistress.
Joven amante.
Out of the way.
Fuera del camino.
Young Mistress, please.
Señorita, por favor.
[Inviting Moon House]
[Casa de la Luna acogedora]
Guess who he's going to talk about today.
¿Adivina de quién va a hablar hoy?
A Ma Gang member died.
Un miembro de Ma Gang murió.
A Chamber of Commerce member died.
Falleció un miembro de la Cámara de Comercio.
I think it's going to be someone from the Lord's Mansion.
Creo que será alguien de la Mansión del Señor.
My bad.
Culpa mía.
Miss Tuoba.
Señorita Tuoba.
I've always wanted to ask you a question.
Siempre quise hacerte una pregunta.
What's that?
¿Qué es eso?
Are your horses
¿Son tus caballos?
all trained?
¿Todos entrenados?
Of course.
Por supuesto.
Why?
¿Por qué?
I checked Xubu Huai's horse.
Revisé el caballo de Xubu Huai.
It was frightened.
Estaba asustado.
On second thought,
Después de madura reflexión,
Ma Gang's horses are specially trained.
Los caballos de Ma Gang están especialmente entrenados.
Even if there was lightning and thunder
Incluso si hubiera relámpagos y truenos
or the carriage on fire,
o el carruaje en llamas,
it shouldn't have reacted like that.
No debería haber reaccionado así.
You're right.
Tienes razón.
What are you trying to say?
¿Qué estás tratando de decir?
I wondered
Me pregunté
if the thunder that day was very close to it.
Si el trueno ese día estaba muy cerca de él.
[Vivid Stories] So many distinguished guests.
[Historias vívidas] Tantos invitados distinguidos.
I'm flattered.
Me siento halagado.
Thank you for coming.
Gracias por venir.
- Thank you. - Good.
-Gracias.-Bien.
Good.
Bien.
Mr. Fang.
Sr. colmillo
Tell us the truth.
Dinos la verdad.
Are you raising a ghost?
¿Estas criando un fantasma?
It's so weird.
Es tan raro.
You told their stories, and they died.
Contaste sus historias y murieron.
Yeah.
Sí.
Tell us.
Cuéntanos.
By seizing command,
Al tomar el mando,
one can attain prosperity and honor.
Uno puede alcanzar prosperidad y honor.
A man with a good heart
Un hombre de buen corazón
cannot do good deeds without money.
No se pueden hacer buenas obras sin dinero.
Guess what, everybody.
¿Adivinen qué, todos?
Guess whose story I'm going to tell today.
¿Adivina de quién es la historia que voy a contar hoy?
Have a guess.
Adivina.
Who is it?
¿Quién es?
Who?
¿OMS?
It's Lei Juekun,
Soy Lei Juekun,
a wealthy businessman in the city.
Un rico hombre de negocios de la ciudad.
Why is it him?
¿Porque es él?
Young Mistress, what can I do for you?
Señorita, ¿qué puedo hacer por usted?
Mr. Fang, your prophetic power
Señor Fang, su poder profético
is getting better and better.
Está mejorando cada vez más.
Young Mistress, I'm innocent.
Señorita, soy inocente.
I...
I...
I don't know who I offended.
No sé a quién ofendí.
They are setting me up.
Me están tendiendo una trampa.
Did the characters in your stories
¿Los personajes de tus historias?
just pop into your head?
¿Simplemente te viene a la cabeza?
No.
No.
My stories are based on Heroes in Xichuan.
Mis historias están basadas en Héroes de Xichuan.
Check it out.
Échale un vistazo.
Look.
Mirar.
We're in the book.
Estamos en el libro.
[Heroes in Xichuan]
[Héroes en Xichuan]
[Fu Sheng, Gu Tian]
[Fu Sheng, Gu Tian]
Why am I not in the book?
¿Por qué no estoy en el libro?
It seems to be a misunderstanding.
Parece ser un malentendido.
You may leave.
Puedes irte.
Yes.
Sí.
What do you think?
¿Qué opinas?
Once he tells a story about someone, they die.
Una vez que cuenta una historia sobre alguien, esa persona muere.
It's not a coincidence.
No es una coincidencia.
He's related to the Water-shaped Jade.
Está relacionado con el Jade en forma de Agua.
He's not as simple as he seems.
No es tan simple como parece.
Okay.
Bueno.
Let's go to the Lei's Mansion tonight.
Vamos a la Mansión Lei esta noche.
The four of us
Nosotros cuatro
will be watching him.
lo estaré observando.
I don't believe he will die.
No creo que muera.
[Lei's Mansion] If Mr. Lei is in good health,
[La Mansión de Lei] Si el Sr. Lei goza de buena salud,
let us see him.
Déjanos verlo.
Yeah, let us see him.
Sí, déjanos verlo.
Yeah.
Sí.
Let us see him.
Vamos a verlo.
We've been waiting for a long time.
Hemos estado esperando durante mucho tiempo.
He won't come out.
Él no saldrá.
Is he dead?
¿Está muerto?
He must have died.
Él debe haber muerto.
Come on.
Vamos.
If they still say bad things,
Si todavía dicen cosas malas,
beat them to a pulp.
golpearlos hasta convertirlos en pulpa.
Yes.
Sí.
Go.
Ir.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Didn't you hear me?
¿No me escuchaste?
No guests tonight.
No hay invitados esta noche.
Do you know this?
¿Sabías esto?
Young Mistress.
Joven amante.
In Xichuan,
En Xichuan,
you don't need to show your token.
No es necesario que muestres tu token.
Everyone knows the beautiful and kind Young Mistress
Todo el mundo conoce a la bella y amable joven amante.
from the Lord's Mansion.
de la Mansión del Señor.
What brings you here?
¿Qué te trae por aquí?
My father ordered me
Mi padre me lo ordenó
to talk to your lord about a deal.
para hablar con tu señor sobre un trato.
Please.
Por favor.
Please go in.
Por favor, entre.
[Lei's Mansion]
[La mansión de Lei]
Young Mistress.
Joven amante.
I didn't know you were here.
No sabía que estabas aquí.
I'm sorry for not greeting you.
Lo siento por no saludarte.
I'm sorry.
Lo lamento.
Have you seen me?
¿Me has visto?
I saw you at the Golden Bloom Banquet
Te vi en el banquete Golden Bloom.
three years ago.
Hace tres años.
I don't really remember.
Realmente no lo recuerdo.
A person of your stature meets so many people.
Una persona de tu estatura conoce a mucha gente.
Young Mistress, what brings you here?
Señorita, ¿qué la trae por aquí?
I'm here to protect you.
Estoy aquí para protegerte.
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
I'm staying at home.
Me quedo en casa.
And I'm not going out.
Y no voy a salir.
He's just a storyteller.
Él es sólo un narrador de historias.
How can he decide whether people live or die?
¿Cómo puede él decidir si la gente vive o muere?
Besides,
Además,
I'm in good health.
Estoy bien de salud.
And I don't have enemies.
Y no tengo enemigos.
How am I going to die tonight?
¿Cómo voy a morir esta noche?
Just in case.
Por si acaso.
I'll examine you.
Te examinaré.
You don't have to.
No tienes por qué hacerlo.
Let him examine you.
Deja que te examine.
Thank you, Young Mistress.
Gracias, joven señora.
My lord.
Mi señor.
You...
Tú...
He's dead.
Él está muerto.
Mr. Fang.
Sr. colmillo
Why are you still writing?
¿Por qué sigues escribiendo?
You know what?
¿Sabes que?
Mr. Lei died last night.
El señor Lei murió anoche.
Who?
¿OMS?
Mr. Lei.
Señor Collar.
I wasted a good piece of cloth.
Desperdicié un buen trozo de tela.
Don't stand still.
No te quedes quieto
Get me a new piece.
Consígueme una pieza nueva
Wait...
Esperar...
Go.
Ir.
You are really unresponsive.
Eres realmente insensible.
Who's there?
¿Quién está ahí?
[Lei Juekun's memorial tablet]
[Placa conmemorativa de Lei Juekun]
My lord.
Mi señor.
You died a terrible death.
Moriste una muerte terrible.
Butler Lei.
Mayordomo Lei.
Mr. Lei died in suspicious circumstances.
El señor Lei murió en circunstancias sospechosas.
Can I do an autopsy on him?
¿Puedo hacerle una autopsia?
My lord died right in front of you.
Mi señor murió justo delante de ti.
You couldn't save him.
No pudiste salvarlo
Do you want to mess with his body?
¿Quieres meterte con su cuerpo?
It happened suddenly.
Pasó de repente.
I didn't have time to cure him.
No tuve tiempo de curarlo.
The murderer killed him
El asesino lo mató
in front of us.
delante de nosotros.
I don't know how many more people he will kill.
No sé cuántas personas más matará.
Stop.
Detener.
You should leave.
Deberías irte.
Alas.
Ay.
We hit it off.
Nos llevamos bien.
I didn't expect you
No te esperaba
to die
morir
half a day after we met.
Medio día después de que nos conocimos.
Alas.
Ay.
I'm sad.
Estoy triste.
Brother.
Hermano.
Let me take one last look at you.
Déjame mirarte una última vez.
Fu Sheng.
Fu Sheng.
Check it out.
Échale un vistazo.
Coming.
Próximo.
Check it out, guys.
Echadle un vistazo, muchachos.
How did this happen?
¿Cómo sucedió esto?
Didn't you see these handprints before?
¿No viste estas huellas de manos antes?
Last night,
Anoche,
I cleaned up his body.
Limpié su cuerpo.
I watched as people put him in.
Observé cómo la gente lo metía allí.
There was nothing on him.
No había nada en él.
Is there...?
Está ahí...?
Is there really a ghost?
¿Existe realmente un fantasma?
[Speak Slowly, Move Fast]
[Habla despacio, muévete rápido]
I want to check his body.
Quiero revisar su cuerpo.
Wait.
Esperar.
It's my lord's body.
Es el cuerpo de mi señor.
You can't touch him.
No puedes tocarlo.
Butler Lei.
Mayordomo Lei.
Don't you think you're talking too much?
¿No crees que estás hablando demasiado?
Madam.
Señora.
Mr. Lei was kind. He had no enemies.
El señor Lei era amable. No tenía enemigos.
About his death,
Sobre su muerte,
I think it was done by an insider.
Creo que lo hizo alguien de adentro.
Is it you,
¿Eres tú?
you,
tú,
or you?
¿o tu?
Madam.
Señora.
I'm loyal
Soy leal
to the Lei family.
A la familia Lei.
Madam.
Señora.
It must be done by an insider.
Esto debe ser realizado por una persona interna.
If you're not the murderer,
Si no eres el asesino,
please allow us to investigate it.
Por favor permítanos investigarlo.
If we can't find anything,
Si no podemos encontrar nada,
the Lord's Mansion will give you an explanation.
La Mansión del Señor te dará una explicación.
Every time you hold a knife,
Cada vez que sostienes un cuchillo,
it's like you're a different person.
Es como si fueras una persona diferente.
Write down what I say.
Escribe lo que digo.
Okay.
Bueno.
Lei Juekun, the deceased,
Lei Juekun, el fallecido,
is 180 centimeters tall.
Mide 180 centímetros de alto.
His physical form is normal.
Su forma física es normal.
His skin color is normal.
Su color de piel es normal.
His head appearance is normal.
La apariencia de su cabeza es normal.
There is no clouding inside his eyes.
No hay ninguna nubosidad en sus ojos.
There are a lot of black viscous liquids in his body.
Hay muchos líquidos negros y viscosos en su cuerpo.
Speak slowly.
Habla despacio.
What's wrong with his head?
¿Qué le pasa en la cabeza?
You don't have to write it.
No tienes que escribirlo
He died of overeating.
Murió por comer en exceso.
What did he eat?
¿Qué comió?
Come on.
Vamos.
Try the tofu.
Prueba el tofu.
Is it delicious?
¿Es delicioso?
No.
No.
It doesn't taste like it used to.
Ya no tiene el mismo sabor que antes.
When we were poor,
Cuando éramos pobres,
we killed three people
Matamos a tres personas
for a piece of tofu.
por un trozo de tofu.
But
Pero
that piece of tofu was sour.
Ese trozo de tofu estaba agrio.
But he said the tofu was delicious.
Pero dijo que el tofu estaba delicioso.
Maybe we killed people for that.
Quizás matamos gente por eso.
That piece of tofu was delicious.
Ese trozo de tofu estaba delicioso.
Seriously.
En serio.
Try the bamboo shoot.
Pruebe el brote de bambú.
Slow down.
Desacelerar.
Before the bamboo shoot grows,
Antes de que crezca el brote de bambú,
it lies dormant in bamboo leaves and mud for three months.
Permanece latente entre hojas de bambú y barro durante tres meses.
If you don't eat it
Si no lo comes
in these three months,
en estos tres meses,
it will grow 10 meters in a day and become bamboo in a few days.
Crecerá 10 metros en un día y se convertirá en bambú en pocos días.
Really?
¿En realidad?
I'm not eating it.
No lo voy a comer
Where are you going?
¿Adónde vas?
I'll plant it.
Lo plantaré.
Come back.
Regresar.
I'm sorry to let you see this.
Lamento dejarte ver esto.
Do you know me?
¿Me conoces?
Yes.
Sí.
You are
Eres
Steward Sun of the Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
Steward Sun de la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei.
Good.
Bien.
Let's get down to business.
Vamos a ir al grano.
How long
Cuánto tiempo
have you been dormant
¿Has estado inactivo?
in Xichuan?
en Xichuan?
Steward Sun.
Mayordomo Sol.
I don't know
No sé
what you're talking about.
De qué estás hablando.
Why did you escape?
¿Por qué escapaste?
I was scared.
Tenía miedo.
What are you afraid of?
¿De qué tienes miedo?
Several people
Varias personas
died in Xichuan.
Murió en Xichuan.
They died
Ellos murieron
after I told their stories.
después de contarles sus historias.
Who would believe
¿Quién lo creería?
that it has nothing to do with me?
¿que no tiene nada que ver conmigo?
What's wrong with me?
¿Qué me pasa?
I...
I...
I don't know what's wrong with me.
No sé qué me pasa.
You're a prophet.
Eres un profeta.
Whatever you say, it happens.
Lo que tú digas, sucede.
No.
No.
All right.
Está bien.
Please do me a favor.
Por favor hazme un favor.
Praise me.
Alábame.
Come on.
Vamos.
You...
Tú...
Praise me.
Alábame.
Steward Sun.
Mayordomo Sol.
You are gifted.
Eres talentoso
You are strong and wise.
Eres fuerte y sabio.
You will have a harem and many children.
Tendrás un harén y muchos hijos.
You will be rich.
Serás rico.
Please spare me.
Por favor perdóname.
I don't want to die.
No quiero morir.
Thank you.
Gracias.
If I die tonight,
Si muero esta noche,
you take the money.
tomas el dinero
With your ability, when you return to Jibei,
Con tu habilidad, cuando regreses a Jibei,
you can join the army. It won't be long
Puedes unirte al ejército. No tardará mucho.
before you become an official.
Antes de convertirse en funcionario.
No.
No.
If I don't die,
Si no muero,
you take the money as well.
Te llevas el dinero también.
Continue being a storyteller.
Sigue siendo un narrador de historias.
Praise Li Zhizhuo of the Jibei Chamber of Commerce.
Elogie a Li Zhizhuo de la Cámara de Comercio de Jibei.
I'd like to see
Me gustaría ver
who's tougher,
¿Quién es más duro?
you or me.
tú o yo.
He died of overeating?
¿Murió por comer demasiado?
No way.
De ninguna manera.
My lord paid attention to his diet.
Mi señor prestó atención a su dieta.
He wouldn't eat too much.
Él no comería demasiado.
It's really hard to believe.
Es realmente difícil de creer.
What did Mr. Lei eat?
¿Qué comió el señor Lei?
Yesterday,
Ayer,
my lord didn't eat at the mansion.
Mi señor no comió en la mansión.
In the morning,
Por la mañana,
he took me to pick up a batch of goods.
Me llevó a recoger un lote de mercancías.
It was a batch of nice silk.
Era un lote de seda bonita.
Stop.
Detener.
Why are they fighting again?
¿Por qué están peleando de nuevo?
Looks like
Parece que
we can't pass in a while.
No podremos pasar por un rato.
We can't wait here.
No podemos esperar aquí.
Look.
Mirar.
Ask all carriages to turn around.
Pedir a todos los vagones que den la vuelta.
We'll go another way.
Iremos por otro camino.
Okay.
Bueno.
Everyone, we'll go another way.
Todos, iremos por otro camino.
Turn around. Go.
Date la vuelta. Vete.
Help. Fire.
Ayuda. Fuego.
Stop. Don't move.
Detente. No te muevas.
Stop.
Detener.
Let everyone keep an eye on the goods.
Que cada uno vigile las mercancías.
Looks like we have to wait.
Parece que tendremos que esperar.
Okay.
Bueno.
We didn't leave the market
No salimos del mercado
until the first quarter of the Shen hour.
hasta el primer cuarto de la hora Shen.
Then, we unloaded the goods in the east of the city.
Luego descargamos las mercancías en el este de la ciudad.
Then,
Entonces,
my lord and I went back to the mansion
Mi señor y yo volvimos a la mansión.
and never went out.
y nunca salió.
What time did you arrive at the mansion?
¿A qué hora llegaste a la mansión?
I think
Creo
it was the You hour.
Era la hora de ti.
Didn't you eat before you got back to the mansion?
¿No comiste antes de regresar a la mansión?
No.
No.
After noon,
Tarde,
my lord was hungry.
Mi señor tenía hambre.
He asked me to buy some dog meat from a peddler.
Me pidió que le comprara carne de perro a un vendedor ambulante.
There was a peddler?
¿Había un vendedor ambulante?
There were many people
Había mucha gente
stuck in traffic.
Atascado en el tráfico.
So, there were peddlers carrying baskets
Entonces, había vendedores ambulantes que llevaban cestas.
and selling dog meat along the street.
y vendiendo carne de perro en la calle.
My lord was wary.
Mi señor estaba cauteloso.
After buying dog meat,
Después de comprar carne de perro,
he tested it with a silver needle to see if it was poisonous.
Lo probó con una aguja de plata para ver si era venenoso.
He didn't eat it until he saw
No lo comió hasta que lo vio.
that the others were fine
que los demás estaban bien
after eating.
después de comer.
What else did he eat after that?
¿Qué más comió después de eso?
After we got back to the mansion,
Después de que regresamos a la mansión,
my lord had a bad appetite.
Mi señor tenía mal apetito.
He didn't eat anything after that.
No comió nada después de eso.
After he got back,
Después de su regreso,
he drank a few bowls of fire-remove soup.
Bebió unos cuantos tazones de sopa quitafuegos.
What?
¿Qué?
It was from the kitchen.
Era de la cocina.
I didn't ask.
No pregunté.
Where is the cook?
¿Dónde está el cocinero?
Cook, get the soup.
Cocinero, trae la sopa.
Butler.
Mayordomo.
It has nothing to do with me.
No tiene nada que ver conmigo.
I heard
Yo oí
our lord went to pick up goods,
Nuestro señor fue a recoger mercancías,
and they stayed in the sun for a long time.
y permanecieron al sol durante mucho tiempo.
There was no water.
No había agua.
And there was a fire.
Y hubo un incendio.
So I made this fire-remove soup.
Así que hice esta sopa quitando el fuego.
It couldn't be poisonous.
No podría ser venenoso.
If you don't believe me,
Si no me crees,
I'll show it to you.
Te lo mostraré.
Beware of him drinking it and committing suicide.
Tenga cuidado de que no lo beba y se suicide.
Stop.
Detener.
Do you want to destroy the evidence?
¿Quieres destruir la evidencia?
You taste everything.
Todo lo pruebas
You'll be poisoned sooner or later.
Serás envenenado tarde o temprano.
It's mung bean soup, right?
Es sopa de frijoles mungo, ¿verdad?
That's right.
Así es.
Eating mung beans with dog meat
Comer frijoles mungo con carne de perro
can cause bloating.
Puede causar hinchazón.
Mr. Lei
Señor collar
ate a lot of dog meat in the afternoon
comí mucha carne de perro por la tarde
and drank
y bebió
a lot of mung bean soup.
Mucha sopa de frijol mungo.
That's why he died of bloating.
Por eso murió de hinchazón.
In that case,
En ese caso,
it's a coincidence, not a murder.
Es una coincidencia, no un asesinato.
I think
Creo
it's weird.
Es raro.
[Wenfu Hall]
[Salón Wenfu]
Lord Wen, what brings you here?
Señor Wen, ¿qué le trae por aquí?
I heard that another person died yesterday.
Escuché que ayer murió otra persona.
Yes.
Sí.
He died of bloating.
Murió de hinchazón.
Your Excellency, Physician Fu.
Su Excelencia, el Doctor Fu.
[Moral and Artistic Stature] Lightning strike, falling from a horse,
[Estatura moral y artística] Caída de un rayo, caída de un caballo,
and bloating.
y hinchazón.
They all died in strange ways.
Todos murieron de formas extrañas.
But we couldn't find anything wrong.
Pero no pudimos encontrar nada malo.
Could it really be a ghost?
¿Podría ser realmente un fantasma?
I don't think so.
No me parece.
Even though
A pesar de
we haven't found a clue yet.
Aún no hemos encontrado ninguna pista.
Me too.
Yo también.
Jibei Chamber of Commerce and the Ma Gang clashed yesterday.
La Cámara de Comercio de Jibei y Ma Gang se enfrentaron ayer.
I arrived in time
Llegué a tiempo
to avoid a disaster.
para evitar un desastre.
If we can't find the murderer,
Si no podemos encontrar al asesino,
no one knows
Nadie lo sabe
when they will go to war.
cuando irán a la guerra.
These things are weird.
Estas cosas son raras.
It's as if someone
Es como si alguien
is controlling Xichuan.
está controlando Xichuan.
No matter how chaotic Xichuan is,
No importa cuán caótico sea Xichuan,
it's my territory.
Es mi territorio.
It doesn't feel good
No se siente bien
that Xichuan is out of my control.
Que Xichuan está fuera de mi control.
Lord Wen, what do you want to do?
Señor Wen, ¿qué desea hacer?
Fu Sheng, you're a good physician.
Fu Sheng, eres un buen médico.
When people are sick, they can be cured.
Cuando las personas están enfermas, se pueden curar.
If the city is sick,
Si la ciudad está enferma,
I think it can be cured, too.
Pienso que también se puede curar.
Diseases have roots.
Las enfermedades tienen raíces.
No matter how deep they hide,
No importa qué tan profundo se escondan,
they are dangerous.
Son peligrosos.
I'll leave it to you.
Te lo dejo a ti.
I'll do my best.
Haré lo mejor que pueda.
Waiter.
Mesero.
You've been working for me
Has estado trabajando para mí
for a while, huh?
por un tiempo ¿eh?
It's been more than two years, master.
Han pasado más de dos años, maestro.
You've
Tú tienes
worked hard
trabajó duro
for the past two years.
durante los últimos dos años.
All right.
Está bien.
Pack your things
Empaca tus cosas
and leave.
y salir.
Okay.
Bueno.
Master.
Maestro.
You didn't give me my salary
No me diste mi sueldo
for the last few years.
Durante los últimos años.
Salary?
¿Salario?
I'm broke
Estoy en la ruina
because of the warehouse fire.
debido al incendio del almacén.
I have no money to pay you.
No tengo dinero para pagarte.
Get out of here.
Sal de aquí.
Master.
Maestro.
You have a big business.
Tienes un gran negocio.
This is just a branch.
Esta es solo una rama.
Can't you pay my salary?
¿No puedes pagar mi sueldo?
Get out.
Salir.
Master, I'm begging you.
Maestro, te lo ruego.
- Please give me my salary - Get out.
- Por favor dame mi sueldo. - Fuera.
Master.
Maestro.
Sir.
Señor.
What can I do for you?
¿Qué puedo hacer por ti?
Your warehouse was on fire yesterday, right?
Tu almacén se incendió ayer, ¿verdad?
May I ask
¿Puedo preguntar?
who you are?
¿Quién eres?
Cut the nonsense.
Basta de tonterías.
I'm from the Lord's Mansion.
Soy de la Mansión del Señor.
I suspect your warehouse fire
Sospecho que tu almacén se incendió
had something to do with Lei Juekun's death.
tuvo algo que ver con la muerte de Lei Juekun.
What?
¿Qué?
What makes you think so?
¿Qué te hace pensar eso?
Save it
Guárdalo
for the Lord's Mansion.
para la Mansión del Señor.
I...
I...
Take me to the warehouse.
Llévame al almacén.
Hurry.
Apurarse.
This way.
Por aquí.
Here it is.
Aquí lo tienes.
The warehouse fire
El incendio del almacén
was an accident.
Fue un accidente.
The weather is dry.
El tiempo está seco.
Maybe a wildfire set some cloth on fire.
Quizás un incendio forestal haya prendido fuego a alguna tela.
What's this?
¿Qué es esto?
It's a gold frame glass mirror.
Es un espejo de cristal con marco dorado.
I got it a few days ago.
Lo conseguí hace unos días.
It's a rare treasure.
Es un tesoro raro.
A merchant
Un comerciante
was robbed by bandits.
Fue robado por bandidos.
It was the only thing he left.
Fue lo único que le quedó.
He pawned it
Él lo empeñó
for travelling expenses.
para gastos de viaje.
Master.
Maestro.
Someone is looking for you.
Alguien te está buscando.
Go.
Ir.
This place is ruined.
Este lugar está arruinado.
There's nothing left here.
No queda nada aquí
All right.
Está bien.
Excuse me.
Disculpe.
Stop.
Detener.
[Fuquan Pawn Shop]
[Casa de empeños Fuquan]
Xiaolong.
Xiaolong.
Why are you back?
¿Por qué has vuelto?
How is it going?
¿Cómo está yendo?
The glass mirror is good.
El espejo de cristal es bueno.
All the ledgers are gone.
Todos los libros de contabilidad han desaparecido.
Good job.
Buen trabajo.
Gu Tian went to the pawn shop
Gu Tian fue a la casa de empeños.
to investigate the fire in the name of the Lord's Mansion.
para investigar el incendio en nombre de la Mansión del Señor.
He found this glass mirror.
Encontró este espejo de cristal.
I was worried he'd notice something wrong.
Me preocupaba que notara que algo andaba mal.
So I stole it.
Así que lo robé.
He chased me for a few blocks.
Me persiguió por unas cuantas cuadras.
You are spotted.
Estás descubierto.
Xiaolong, don't worry.
Xiaolong, no te preocupes.
I got rid of him.
Me deshice de él.
You two, go out and have a look.
Ustedes dos, salgan y echen un vistazo.
Yes.
Sí.
Physician Fu, it's time to eat.
Doctor Fu, es hora de comer.
Gu Tian hasn't come back.
Gu Tian no ha regresado.
You eat first.
Come primero.
No way.
De ninguna manera.
Let's wait for him.
Vamos a esperarlo.
If you're hungry, eat first.
Si tienes hambre, come primero.
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
I'm starving.
Estoy hambriento.
- I'm starving. - Gu is back.
- Me muero de hambre. - Gu ha vuelto.
You're finally back. We've been waiting for you.
Por fin has vuelto. Te estábamos esperando.
Let's eat.
Vamos a comer.
I'm starving.
Estoy hambriento.
Where have you been?
¿Dónde has estado?
The Fuquan Pawn Shop
La casa de empeños de Fuquan
Feng Qianli took us to the other day
Feng Qianli nos llevó el otro día
caught fire yesterday.
Se incendió ayer.
The pawn shop caught fire.
La casa de empeños se incendió.
They probably wanted
Probablemente querían
to destroy the ledgers we had seen.
para destruir los libros de contabilidad que habíamos visto.
There is nothing left.
No queda nada
The owner said the cause of the fire was dry weather.
El propietario dijo que la causa del incendio fue el clima seco.
But I found something there.
Pero encontré algo allí.
It's a glass mirror. A merchant pawned it for travelling expenses.
Es un espejo de cristal. Un comerciante lo empeñó para pagar gastos de viaje.
It gathers heat in the sun.
Acumula calor en el sol.
I guess
Supongo
it was used to start the fire.
Fue utilizado para iniciar el fuego.
The fire was intentional.
El incendio fue intencional.
Where's the mirror?
¿Dónde está el espejo?
When I wasn't looking,
Cuando no estaba mirando,
a guy stole it.
Un tipo lo robó.
It's weird.
Es raro.
Xubu Huai died of a lightning strike.
Xubu Huai murió al ser alcanzado por un rayo.
The groom has also got off the carriage.
El novio también se bajó del carruaje.
Hua Lei died of falling from a horse.
Hua Lei murió al caerse de un caballo.
That alley has a secret.
Ese callejón tiene un secreto.
Lei Juekun died of bloating.
Lei Juekun murió de hinchazón.
Someone knew that he ate dog meat at noon.
Alguien sabía que comía carne de perro al mediodía.
He only needed
Él solo necesitaba
to be careful
tener cuidado
to kill them without anyone noticing.
para matarlos sin que nadie se dé cuenta.
Why did he do that?
¿Por qué hizo eso?
What can he get out of this?
¿Qué puede sacar de esto?
Anyway,
De todos modos,
we need to get to the truth quickly.
Necesitamos llegar a la verdad rápidamente.
Maybe someday it will be our turn.
Quizás algún día nos toque a nosotros.
Don't you eat it?
¿No lo comes?
Guys.
Tipo.
What do you think?
¿Qué opinas?
I think we have a good life.
Creo que tenemos una buena vida.
He wanted to say
Él quería decir
that we had lived a dangerous life
que habíamos vivido una vida peligrosa
all these years.
Todos estos años.
It's not easy
No es fácil
for us to live
para que vivamos
a stable life.
una vida estable.
Yeah.
Sí.
You're right.
Tienes razón.
There's a storyteller
Hay un narrador de historias
who's jinxing our master.
¿Quién está gafando a nuestro amo?
If something happens to him,
Si algo le pasa,
we'll have to live a poor life again.
Tendremos que vivir una vida pobre otra vez.
We have to stop him.
Tenemos que detenerlo.
He wanted to say
Él quería decir
that our master would be safe
que nuestro amo estaría a salvo
if we silenced Fang.
Si silenciamos a Fang.
Yeah.
Sí.
Wait.
Esperar.
Is there anything else you'd like to say?
¿Hay algo más que quieras decir?
Okay.
Bueno.
If so,
En ese caso,
we'll do what he said.
Haremos lo que él dijo.
Okay.
Bueno.
Let's go to the Inviting Moon House tomorrow
Vamos mañana a la Casa de la Luna Invitadora.
and silence Fang.
y silencio Fang.
But
Pero
if we screw up,
Si nos equivocamos,
he's the one to blame.
Él es el culpable.
Yeah.
Sí.
Wait. No, brother.
Espera. No, hermano.
It's interesting.
Es interesante.
Go.
Ir.
Come to our house for a drink.
Ven a nuestra casa a tomar una copa.
Here we go.
Aquí vamos.
Here.
Aquí.
Brother.
Hermano.
Does he dare to come today?
¿Se atreverá a venir hoy?
If he comes, we'll teach him a lesson.
Si viene le daremos una lección.
It was his fault
Fue su culpa
that the girl from Ma Gang grabbed me
Que la chica de Ma Gang me agarró
and interrogated me for days.
y me interrogaron durante días.
If you want to teach him a lesson, you should come a few days earlier.
Si quieres darle una lección, deberías venir unos días antes.
You don't think he dares to come.
No crees que se atreva a venir.
Stop bluffing.
Deja de fanfarronear.
What do you know?
¿Qué sabes?
I'm kind.
Soy amable
All right. You're kind.
Está bien. Eres amable.
Here he comes.
Aquí viene.
Bro, hit him.
Hermano, golpéalo.
Go.
Ir.
- Good! - Good!
- ¡Bien! - ¡Bien!
Good.
Bien.
Thank you for coming all the way
Gracias por venir hasta el final
to listen to my story.
para escuchar mi historia.
As usual,
Como siempre,
I don't talk about the past, only the present.
No hablo del pasado, sólo del presente.
Screw you.
Púdrete.
Get away.
Escapar.
Hero, what's the matter?
Héroe, ¿qué pasa?
Ask yourself.
Pregúntate a ti mismo.
You're a jinx.
Eres un gafe.
You got some heroes
Tienes algunos héroes
in the city killed.
En la ciudad asesinado.
I'm innocent.
Soy inocente.
You must have misunderstood me.
Debes haberme entendido mal.
Shut up.
Callarse la boca.
Guys.
Tipo.
Yes.
Sí.
Take away his things.
Quitadle sus cosas.
No.
No.
Hero.
Héroe.
Those are my tools
Esas son mis herramientas
for making a living.
para ganarse la vida.
Let go.
Déjalo ir.
Screw you.
Púdrete.
Go.
Ir.
I don't talk about the past, only the present.
No hablo del pasado, sólo del presente.
I'll praise the Three Heroes of Xichuan.
Alabaré a los Tres Héroes de Xichuan.
Each of them is a hero.
Cada uno de ellos es un héroe.
Shut up.
Callarse la boca.
You cursed us.
Nos maldijiste.
I'll kill you.
Te mataré.
Stop.
Detener.
The Young Mistress is here.
La joven amante está aquí.
Young Mistress.
Joven amante.
Leader.
Líder.
What's wrong with you?
¿Qué sucede contigo?
How dare you bully him?
¿Cómo te atreves a intimidarlo?
Leave here.
Salir de aquí.
Don't disturb us.
No nos molestes.
Go.
Ir.
Good thing I didn't go up.
Menos mal que no subí.
Look how miserable they are.
Mira qué miserables son.
Will they die?
¿Morirán?
They made a scene.
Hicieron una escena.
They will die.
Ellos morirán.
Will the three of them die tonight?
¿Morirán los tres esta noche?
If they die,
Si mueren,
I'll never
Yo nunca lo haré
clear my name.
Limpia mi nombre.
What do we do now?
¿Qué hacemos ahora?
If we want to find out the relationship
Si queremos descubrir la relación
between the storyteller and the murderer,
Entre el narrador y el asesino,
we should keep an eye
Deberíamos mantenernos atentos
on Fang Zhiyuan
en Fang Zhiyuan
and your three men.
y tus tres hombres.
We have to split into two groups.
Tenemos que dividirnos en dos grupos.
Miss Tuoba and I know martial arts.
La señorita Tuoba y yo sabemos artes marciales.
I'll go with Fu Sheng.
Iré con Fu Sheng.
Miss Tuoba goes with Wen Jue.
La señorita Tuoba va con Wen Jue.
In this way, everyone is safe.
De esta manera, todos están seguros.
No.
No.
I don't know her well.
No la conozco bien.
Then...
Entonces...
Miss Tuoba goes with Fu Sheng.
La señorita Tuoba va con Fu Sheng.
I'll protect the Young Mistress.
Protegeré a la Joven Señora.
All right?
¿Está bien?
No.
No.
You always piss me off.
Siempre me cabreas.
How about this?
¿Qué tal esto?
I'll go with Fu Sheng.
Iré con Fu Sheng.
You keep an eye on Fang.
Mantén vigilado a Fang.
You don't know martial arts.
No sabes artes marciales.
What if you encounter the murderer?
¿Qué pasa si te encuentras con el asesino?
No one dares to hurt me in Xichuan.
Nadie se atreve a hacerme daño en Xichuan.
Miss Tuoba, what do you say?
Señorita Tuoba, ¿qué dice?
Nice.
Lindo.
Don't even think about it.
Ni lo pienses
Stay away from her.
Manténgase alejado de ella.
Do you like her?
¿Te gusta ella?
If you piss her off, she'll stab you.
Si la enojas, te apuñalará.
I'll have to stitch you up.
Tendré que coserte.
Don't look for trouble.
No busques problemas
Brother.
Hermano.
[Mutton soup]
[Sopa de cordero]
He just talked about us.
Él acaba de hablar de nosotros.
We'll be fine,
Estaremos bien,
right?
¿bien?
Brother.
Hermano.
I...
I...
I'm scared.
Tengo miedo.
What do we do?
¿Qué hacemos?
Do I look like I know what to do?
¿Parece que sé qué hacer?
Let's hide away.
Vamos a escondernos.
Let's find an open space
Encontremos un espacio abierto
to stay a night.
pasar la noche.
Good idea.
Buena idea.
An open space has a good view.
Un espacio abierto tiene una buena vista.
No one can hide there.
Nadie puede esconderse allí.
If someone approaches us,
Si alguien se acerca a nosotros,
we can run.
Podemos correr.
Good for you.
Bien por usted.
We'll light a bonfire,
Encenderemos una hoguera,
hold a girl,
abrazar a una chica,
and drink some wine.
y beber un poco de vino.
The night will soon be over.
La noche pronto terminará.
Okay. Let's do it.
Está bien. Hagámoslo.
He's right.
Él tiene razón.
Go.
Ir.
Fang.
Colmillo.
There are only a few eggs left in the kitchen.
Sólo quedan unos pocos huevos en la cocina.
Let's not cook.
No cocinemos.
Let's go to the restaurant across the street.
Vamos al restaurante de enfrente.
It's up to you.
Tu decides.
What do you want to eat?
¿Qué quieres comer?
My treat.
Es mi invitación.
You're so arrogant.
Eres tan arrogante.
I'll eat this.
Me comeré esto
Fried eggs?
¿Huevos fritos?
Don't touch things you don't know.
No toques cosas que no conoces.
No one can poison raw eggs.
Nadie puede envenenar los huevos crudos.
Have a taste.
Pruebalo.
Don't you dare?
¿No te atreves?
Give it to me if you don't dare.
Dámelo si no te atreves.
It's not bad.
No está mal.
It's
Es
not enough.
No es suficiente.
There are only a few eggs left.
Sólo quedan unos pocos huevos.
It's not enough for us.
No es suficiente para nosotros
You eat more.
Comes más.
What are you writing?
¿Qué estás escribiendo?
The story I'll tell next time.
La historia la contaré la próxima vez.
What's the story about?
¿De qué trata la historia?
I'm going to talk
Voy a hablar
about two famous young heroes in Xichuan.
Sobre dos jóvenes héroes famosos en Xichuan.
Fu Sheng
Fu Sheng
and Gu Tian.
y Gu Tian.
[Young Heroes: Fu Sheng, Gu Tian]
[Jóvenes héroes: Fu Sheng, Gu Tian]
Hulu.
Hulu.
Have you forgotten
¿Lo has olvidado?
how Fu Sheng ignored you in the first place?
¿Cómo fue que Fu Sheng te ignoró en primer lugar?
[The animals in the show are props]
[Los animales del espectáculo son accesorios]
[No animals were harmed during the filming]
[Ningún animal resultó dañado durante el rodaje]
♪Under the sky, light and shadow go together♪
♪Bajo el cielo, la luz y la sombra van juntas♪
♪The reflection of prosperity and splendor♪
♪El reflejo de la prosperidad y el esplendor♪
♪Hides many secrets♪
♪Esconde muchos secretos♪
♪It's like♪
♪Es como♪
♪Every page of your life♪
♪Cada página de tu vida♪
♪It's all about destiny♪
♪Todo es cuestión del destino♪
♪The story has tragedy and comedy♪
♪La historia tiene tragedia y comedia♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪Para descubrir el misterio♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪Nos vamos de aventuras♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪No huimos ni nos comprometemos fácilmente♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪Cuando llega el amanecer♪
♪The light shines♪
♪La luz brilla♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪Seguimos el camino del descubrimiento♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪Para perseguir y dar la bienvenida♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪Cada historia desconocida♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪Hacemos un viaje juntos♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪Con sangre caliente y propósito original♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪Aprovechamos el día y lo vivimos al máximo♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪Deja una huella en nuestro viaje♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪Dispersa la oscuridad con nuestros corazones♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪Aspira a marcar la diferencia♪
♪To discover the mystery♪
♪Para descubrir el misterio♪
♪We go on adventures♪
♪Nos vamos de aventuras♪
♪We don't run away or compromise easily♪
♪No huimos ni nos comprometemos fácilmente♪
♪When dawn comes♪
♪Cuando llega el amanecer♪
♪The light shines♪
♪La luz brilla♪
♪We follow the path of discovery♪
♪Seguimos el camino del descubrimiento♪
♪To chase and welcome♪
♪Para perseguir y dar la bienvenida♪
♪Every unknown story♪
♪Cada historia desconocida♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪Hacemos un viaje juntos♪
♪With hot blood and original purpose♪
♪Con sangre caliente y propósito original♪
♪We seize the day and live it to the fullest♪
♪Aprovechamos el día y lo vivimos al máximo♪
♪Leave a mark on our journey♪
♪Deja una huella en nuestro viaje♪
♪Scatter the darkness with our hearts♪
♪Dispersa la oscuridad con nuestros corazones♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪Aspira a marcar la diferencia♪
♪Make a difference♪
♪Haz la diferencia♪
♪We take a trip together♪
♪Hacemos un viaje juntos♪
♪Through hardships♪
♪A través de las dificultades♪
♪We will find the glory♪
♪Encontraremos la gloria♪
♪Aspire to make a difference♪
♪Aspira a marcar la diferencia♪